頼む　ナックル!!
Ten. The ability to build up a shroud of Nen aura.
チクショ！　あの野郎 俺を…　俺を…
You can make your body harder,
and considerably slow the effects of aging. Zetsu.
ゴミみたいに見やがった!!
A technique that nullifies your Nen aura. It is effective for concealing your presence, and recovering from extreme fatigue.
おう！　任せろ！
This ability is crucial for increasing your power.
師匠　すんません！ 俺達　バカなんです
Hatsu. The release of your Nen aura, after boosting via Ren.
世界より大事なものが あるんです！
These four elements are known
as the four major principles, and are critical to the mastery of Nen.
中央塔３階は
But I'm itching to fight right now!
モラウの「スモーキージェイル」が 緩衝材となり 破壊は免れたものの
Fierce x And x Ferocious
本来あるべき場所から やや左へ飛ばされ 危うい均衡の中　かろうじて 建物の体裁を維持していた
Gon is in his first 200s match, but he's been caught off guard
by the unexpected nature of his opponent's attack.
うお!!
He's been hit from behind by another top!
ひねりつぶしてやるから 出て来やがれ！
Gon is in big trouble, after having been surrounded by Dancing Tops!
必ず　奴は　また現れる
Clean hit and knockdown!
爆発寸前の 俺の隙を突くために 時間です　利息が…。
Gido has already earned four points! Can you continue? You bet! There are too many tops for me to track.
うるせぇ!!
Damn... What should I do?
ユピーが 偽りの怒りに身を委ね
M-Master...
ナックルを誘い込むため 気炎を上げている時…
Is he using Nen? Yes, that is a form of Hatsu.
外で何が起こっていようと 俺は　こいつを拘束する！
He's projecting his aura into the tops. That allows the tops to move with more strength and
speed than normally possible.
それで　いいはずだ！
Manipulating a small object requires
only a small amount of aura.
約１００兆匹 煙の粒子と粒子の 隙間をすり抜けるほど
A large object requires a
larger amount of aura.
微小な生物群が 相対するモラウには
Gido is also using Nen in other ways here.
決して気付かれることのない 間隔を保ちながら
Those tops couldn't be so strong
ゆっくりとではあるが　確実に
were he simply using his aura to spin them. It can only be accomplished
「スモーキージェイル」からの 脱出を成し遂げつつあった
because he cares deeply about his tops. Objects respond well
宮殿北部の地下には
to those who are compatible.
トンボを連想させる形の 巨大な倉庫群が広がっている
I can't follow them with my eyes.
Ｄエリア　羽の先端部に
I can sense it.
ビゼフが　ひそかに私物化し 女性達を囲っている倉庫がある
Yeah, I can sense them.
マルコスの情報によって 場所を特定していたイカルゴは
My Ten is fading!
目的地に向かい 約５ｋｍほどの直線道路を
Another direct hit! Gon is completely helpless!
トラックで駆けていた
He's been knocked out of the ring!
イカルゴの前方に Ａ・Ｂエリアへの
The score is now 6-0!
分岐点を認めたのと 時を同じくして
He's dug himself a big hole! It won't work...
「サテライトンボ」が 先に倉庫へ　たどり着いた あっ！
If I focus on sensing the tops, my Ten shroud will dissolve.
扉が開いている
What should I do?
このケースは吉兆！
A top was knocked outside the ring?
パームがビゼフを眠らせ 宮殿へ向かい
But it isn't attacking me...
慌てたビゼフが 施錠を忘れて　その後を追った
What's wrong? Can you continue fighting? Be quiet! I'm thinking right now.
…という可能性が高い はっ！
If you're not in the ring within a ten-count,
I'll rule you the loser!
ブロヴーダが 警備兵エリアに！
Now that I think about it, the Nen in this top didn't feel hostile. What about the others?
それは　イカルゴにとって
They're spinning around,
bumping into each other.
ブロヴーダとの対決が不可避で あることを意味していた
Maybe the tops aren't actually targeting me? Four! Why are you standing outside the ring?
ブロヴーダが 俺に疑問を持っている…
If I stay in the ring, I'll get hurt! Five!
なぜ？
Just as I thought...
俺が何かミスを？
This is like a game of sumo tops!
冷静になれ… 奴が気付けること 気付けないことを
It's impossible to command tops
to move with precision.
冷静に分けるんだ！
It's likely Gido simply commands the tops
生き残るために！
to strike anything in their way.
さっきのやりとりで 疑惑を生む何かがあった
They spin around, striking whatever happens to cross their paths. Seven!
フラッタに扮した俺の何かが 不自然だった？
In that case, I don't need to fear the tops.
確かに　ハギャの命令で 地下に行くって言い訳が
I can ignore the tops, and attack him!
すでに　不自然といえば不自然だ だけど　あの場で 即座に追及されなかったのは
Heh, you may have figured out my tops, but you still can't land an attack!
ミスが致命的なものではなく
There it is!
ブロヴーダの心の隅に 薄く差した
Gido's special technique,
combining offense and defense!
影のようなものだった ということ
Tornado Top!
ブロヴーダは その影の正体を確かめるために
He lands a strong counter on Gon!
ごまかし切れる程度の ミスなのか？
Three points! The judge has awarded a
critical hit and knockdown!
それとも 最後の確認が欲しいだけの
Gido has nine points!
大きなミスなのか？
Gon is on the verge of losing!
楽観は　できない 大きなミスと見るべき 誰か　いないか？
I turn myself into a top to protect myself, while using my Dancing Tops to attack.
われは長官の使者である！ 返答次第… いや　隙を見せたら
My strategy might be boring, but it's effective for racking up points.
その場で攻撃されるくらいの 覚悟でいないと
There are a number of ways to defeat Gido. You can attack him until
殺られる！
he tires, and his Ten begins to fade.
われは長官の使者！
You can use Hatsu that overpowers his defense.
長官の命によって　ここへ来た！ シンカー・ベル！
Both methods require a large amount of aura.
いるならば　至急 われと共に来られたし！ ビゼフの倉庫に
However, Gon-kun doesn't know Ren, the technique to instantly generate aura.
使いの者の来ることは 決してない これは　パームに仲間であることを 示すための符丁である
Learning how to quickly
create large amounts of aura, and how to channel it into attacks, requires endless training and
combat experience to learn.
いるならば なぜ返答しないのだ？
He'd need five more years
before he could fight Gido.
他に人は？ わ…　私は 外のことは何も…。
I'm sure he's beginning to realize that now.
長官殿以外の人間との コンタクトを
What should I do?
禁じられておりますので。
What will it take to prolong this match?
彼女は　これが
If he scores one more point, it's over.
長官による　忠誠心を測る 試験だと思っていた
But I want to keep fighting.
他の女達も　ほぼ同様である
What can I do right now?
「ビゼフからの連絡専用電話が あるにもかかわらず
That would be...
使者が来るのは　おかしい」 というのが疑問の根拠であり
Gon!
平常心を奪われずに
He released his Ten?
命令を守れるかを試されている」と 捉えた彼女達は
That's reckless!
イカルゴとの会話を固く拒んだ
But he didn't simply release it. That's... Zetsu...
しかし　それはイカルゴにとって 好都合であった
The technique for concealing your presence!
ここか…
Your aura also disappears because
your micropyles are sealed.
彼女達の生存確率は この場に残っているほうが はるかに高いのだ
Any aura that normally escapes
your body is also nullified, so he has no Nen protection! I didn't teach him Zetsu use!
他者の命に気を配り
Did he learn it on his own, before we met?
ましてや　守る余裕など イカルゴには全くなかった
In that case, he wouldn't realize
that this is Zetsu.
あった！　念文字！
He must have learned it while
オーラによって ひそかに記された文字は
attempting to track a beast or other target...
「凝」によってのみ 読み取ることが可能となる
The boy certainly has incredible potential.
紙や機器に伝言を残すよりも
But why would he use it now,
in this situation?
ビゼフに見つかるリスクが 低いとの判断である
Idiot!
「宮殿へ」 「決行時まで連絡なき場合
If you're hit by a Nen attack, without protection,
you'll be totally messed up! I know that.
亡き者として行動されたし」 分かっていたことであったが
But in order to track the tops' complex
pathing with only sensations to go on, I must focus all my senses...
イカルゴは 体の一部を失ったような
Could it be that
心の痛みを感じた
he never expected to win? He's risking his life...
パーム…
Risking his life to train?
((もし　パームの死　あるいは
You don't want to live, kid?
それに準じる事態に際したら 「サテライトンボ」と 電波通信を使って
Then I'll help you die!
((軍団長に状況を教える体裁で
What?!
実は　メレオロンに情報を与える))
Amazing!
((虚実を混ぜて　敵を 翻弄するってことだな))
It's the first time Gon has managed
to evade an attack!
)
I can feel them...
それには　メレオロンの存在と
I know where they're heading!
俺の裏切りが バレていないことが大前提
This is all I can do right now...
つまり 俺に疑惑を抱き始めている
Concentrate on dodging
my opponent's attacks!
ええ　まぁ　大体。 ハギャ…　ね。
Your right radius and ulna were both broken.
んっ？
Fractured humerus.
あいつ　そう呼ぶと怒るんだろ？ あっ！
Three broken ribs. Twelve other minor fractures.
あぁ…。
Four months before you're
completely healed up.
はい　偽者死亡。
Man, why do you think
Four-Eyes was training us?
あぁ？　空？ まぁ　いいや あとはハギャに聞けば。
I took a few hits, but I wasn't in mortal danger, as long
as he missed my vital spots...
あとは　ブロヴーダが他の連中に それを報告してくれれば
Uh, sorry...
何て名前だよ!?
What were you thinking?!
俺のほうが名前を 知らなかったことは真実なのに
Didn't you see those who'd suffered
the traditional Nen greeting? You could have ended up just like them!
果たして奴らが それをすんなり信用するか？
Oh, that's what I just told him.
遭遇した時
Honestly...
奴らが納得するだけの理由を 考えないと…
I'm glad you weren't injured any worse.
いや　ダメだ！
Wing-san, I really am sorry.
あれは ハギャの改名を知らない奴は敵 …と決め込んだ証拠！
No, I won't let this one slide. Killua-kun, do you know when Gon-kun will
have recovered completely?
見つかったらバトル
The doctor said it would take two months.
その覚悟で 上に戻らなきゃダメだ！
I understand.
あぁ？
In that case, I won't allow you to participate in
any matches for two months!
はっ！ エレベーターが 上に行かない！
I won't allow you to train in,
or study about, Nen.
まさか　あいつ 暗証番号のシステムを知らずに 降りて来た？
If you don't abide by these rules, I will never teach you again.
チャンス！ 絶好の二者択一！
Well? I understand. I'll do as you say.
「ハコワレ」が発動して もうすぐ５分経つ
It will be a visual reminder of your promise.
そうすれば 貸したオーラは７０００に迫る
Killua-kun, a moment, please.
この数値なら　一括返済 されることはないのか？ 直撃…　直撃さえ避ければ…！
Killua-kun, what is the true objective
you two are pursuing? Well, we don't really have an objective.
最悪なのは 「ハコワレ」が消滅し
Before running into Zushi and you, my plan was to earn some quick cash.
かつ　俺自身がダメージを 受けるほどの攻撃を食らうこと
Gon's here to train hard,
so he can defeat a guy named Hisoka.
そうなるくらいなら このまま時間を稼いで 奴が　とぶのを待ったほうが 断然いい
That's it, really. Looks like the others in the 200s
want to reach the top floor.
おら！
Battle Olympia, was it?
けど それだと　まだ　１０分以上は
I'm not too interested.
ただ　じっと　時間が過ぎるのを 待たなきゃいけねえ
Oh, Gon is... Well, I'm not sure...
シュートは… シュートは　それじゃ持たねえ！ 何としても 奴をもう一回　爆発させる
He said that he only wants to fight Hisoka.
でないと　間に合わねえ！ けりがつく前に シュートが死んじまう！
But after seeing his match yesterday, I have a feeling he enjoys the thrills...
元気だな　化け物！
How long will this exchange continue?
掛かった　俺の罠に 偽りの怒りの演技に
There are nearly fifty tops flying
around the ring!
この　まとわり付くクソハエを 黙らせろ！ こいつが　ピチクわめくたびに
Gon is evading the frightening
whirlwind of tops! Gido has used up all of his tops, and can only watch with the rest of us!
てめぇの面が　ちらついて ムカつく！
Not that way!
さぁ　いつでも爆発してやるぜ フフフ… 正確には　爆発するふりだがな
There's nowhere to run...
時間です　利息が…。 あ！　うるせぇんだよ!!
You say that he was enjoying a situation
奴は必ず　その隙を突いて来る
that could have cost him his life? Yeah.
だが　冷静に平常に怒れば
I know because I've felt the same way.
膨張は　必ずコントロールできる
Although I take circumstances
into consideration, too.
今すぐ　こいつを外せ！
Once he's in the zone, he loses sight of everything else. Oh!
さもねえと…　殺す！
But he isn't the type to break a
promise twice, so you needn't worry.
てめぇら全員　跡形もなくすぞ クズども！
Perhaps I have... It's too late.
生じる奴の隙を　俺が突く
Because Gon and I already know.
そりゃ無理だ　でくの坊。 お前　ここで這いつくばって 死ぬんだよ。
If you regret teaching us
and decide to back out, we'll find someone else,
or we'll learn it ourselves. You don't have to feel responsible.
次… 次の利息宣言がゴング どっちがゴキブリか 教えてやるよ。
My brother and Hisoka can both use Nen, so Gon and I were bound to
discover it eventually. I understand.
フフっ。
And I mean to finish what I started.
フッハッハッハ フッ…　ハッハッハッハッハ。
There are many things I must tell you.
フッハッハッハッハ。
Zushi is waiting in my lodge. You can train with him.
時間です　利息が付きます。
No, I'll pass. Huh?
くっ！
I won't leave Gon behind.
おら!!
If he keeps his promise,
I'll start training when he does. Tell Gon-kun this...
行ける！　このタイミングなら 確実に１発…　いや　２発！
I will allow him to practice the other "Nen"! Tell him to practice "Ten" daily!
しかし　おっかしいな　俺
Hey, Gon.
死ぬ気で戦って
Master...
殺されることすら 覚悟してる相手を　シカト!?
I may have
武士の情けもねえのか！ アリ野郎！ うぅ！　マジ ますますムカついて来たぜ！
awakened an incredible beast...
まだ　拳　振り上げてる途中？
Master?
周りが すげぇスローになるって…
What do you mean?
死ぬ前の…
You found the agency on your own, so you must be sharp. But I can't recommend you to
one of our valued clients.
かはっ！ 膨張を途中で止めた！
Some clients don't mind greenhorns. But it isn't experience alone that you lack.
ヘヘっ。 やられた！
What do you mean? I said that I have a Hunter License!
こいつ　クールだった！
But your exam hasn't ended yet.
止め…　らんねえ…
I can tell. What?
シュート　悪い！　しくった！
Can you see anything? Eh? Next to me.
シュート…　ボス… みんな…
That's the bare minimum.
あとは　頼む…
What does she mean? What is it that I cannot see?
うぅ…。
You can't see it, but you can sense it.
やった！　やった！　やった！
Well, I was just playing with you.
無理！　もう無理！　やっべぇ！ 俺　完全に死にかけた！
Fate had a hand in crossing our paths.
花畑　見えた！ まずは　シュートを 病院に連れて行かねえと！
Consider this advice from a veteran...
シャ！ ８発　入れてやったぜ！ ヒャッハッハッハ！
You didn't notice when I stole this, and you didn't notice when I walked past you.
うぉっほ！
Bastard... Return my Hunter License!
何が…　起きた？
Can a newbie who knows nothing of Nen defeat me?
完全にハメたはず…
Nen?
決まってる… 別方向からの攻撃に 気付かなかったのだ
Wanna give it a try?
全く気付かないなど…
Understand now?
その前もそうだ この目障りな生物も 突然　俺に憑いた
You still lack something.
何の前触れもなく
I...
んっ？
I need...
あいつは
I'll be your teacher.
さっき階段で会った…
The real exam has only just begun.
んっ？
Gon's hidden potential begins to awaken.
悪いけど これから　あんたにすること
And Kurapika has also encountered
全部　ただの八つ当たりだから。
a new power that will help propel him forward.